Vini Salazar, BSc

Biologist, Programmer, Scientific Diver

viniws@gmail.com | GitHub | Lattes

About

Biologist turned programmer focusing on the marine environment, specially microbial ecology.

I am passionate about the oceans, microbes, computers and teaching programming to other biologists and scientists. If you need more info about my academic work, please visit my Lattes page listed above (available in Portuguese

only).

Feel free to reach out by e-mail or through my GitHub profile.

Currently

Bioinformatician at Neoprospecta Microbiome Technologies.

Autonomous researcher at GOC.

Technologies

Python, R, SQL, Git, UNIX Data and Bio Stack:

Numpy Scipy Pandas Matplotlib BioPython

Expertise

Genomic analysis, including but not limited to:

16S rRNA gene surveys Genome assembly SNP analysis

Informatics and programming education

Backend development with Django, database management

Statistics, Data visualization

Scientific diving, Reef Check protocols

Benchtop activities and good laboratory practices

Other skills

PADI OWSI instructor EFR First Aid instructor

Extensive onboard experience Great communication and writing skills

English proficiency (IELTS and TOEFL exams)

Research interests

Bioinformatics, microbial ecology, marine genomics, biological oceanography, scientific diving, programming education

Education

2012-2018 Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina, Brazil

BSc Biological Sciences

Dissertation: "Programming education for biologists" available here (Portuguese only).

2014-2015 The University of Queensland, Australia

CNPq Science Without Borders study abroad student

Professional

experience

2018 - pres**Neoprospecta Microbiome Technologies** - Florianópolis, Brazil

Bioinformatic analysis

Backend development with Django

2016 - 2018 Phycology Laboratory, UFSC - Florianópolis, Brazil

Junior researcher

Algae physiology and response to climate change

Scientific diving

2013-2017 Agua Viva Diving - Florianópolis, Brazil

SCUBA diving instructor

2015 **Crystal Divers** - Bali, Indonesia

Professional Divemaster Internship

2015 Australian Institute of Marine Science- Townsville, Australia

Research assistant Molecular biology laboratory

Awards

2012 CAPES scholarship 'Young Talents in Science'

2014 CNPq study abroad scholarship 'Science Without Borders'